Guide to the Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Martin R. Kaatz 1953-1993
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Martin R. Kaatz
1953-1993
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
FP-0017
Kaatz, Martin R.
15.50 cubic feet 29 boxes 25 letter sized document cases, 2 legal sized document cases, 1 legal half sized document case, and one oversize map drawer Correspondence, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings, photographs, maps, slides, and reports in good condition.
The Martin R. Kaatz papers consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, newspaper clippings and reports related to environmental programs and organizations in Kittitas and Yakima counties of Washington State.
Biographical Note
Martin R. Kaatz was born on April 16, 1924, in Cleveland, Ohio, to David and Ella Kaatz. As a child his family relocated to Detroit, Michigan, where he attended public schools and graduated from Central High School in 1942. After graduation he attended the University of Michigan but remained only one semester before joining the United States Army in 1943. He returned to the University of Michigan after he was discharged from the service in 1946. He received his bachelor’s degree in 1948 and a year later his master's degree in geography. From 1949 to 1950 he attended Syracuse University’s doctorial program in geography, but returned to the University of Michigan where he received his Ph.D. in 1952. In October of 1952, he was hired by Central Washington College of Education (presently Central Washington University) as an Assistant Professor of Geography. Dr. Kaatz served as chairman of the Geography Department for fifteen years. He remained as an instructor at the college until his retirement in December of 1982.
The papers in this collection contain the meeting minutes of the Downtown Ellensburg Task Force (1979-1987), Ellensburg Planning Commission (1960-1966), Yakima River Basin Citizen’s Committee (1974-1977) and the Yakima River Basin Steering Committee (1973-1974). Included in the collection are plans, proposals and drafts of programs and reports related to county and city zoning ordinances, water quality, ecological management and the initiation of an environmental studies program at Central Washington University.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Arranged alphabetically by subject heading and type of material
Open to the public
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Kaatz, Martin R.
Central Washington University. Dept. of Geography and Land Studies
Kittitas County (Wash.); Yakima County (Wash.); Ellensburg (Wash.)
City planning--20th century; Universities & colleges--United States; Environmental management
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
College administrators--United States
- Agricultural Lands Task Force, 1973-1993 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Agricultural Return Flow Management Plan, 1975 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Big Bend Basin Level B Study of Water and Related Land Resources, 1975 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Downtown Taskforce Minutes, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Downtown Taskforce Minutes, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Ellensburg Comprehensive Plan Proposal, 1962 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Ellensburg Proposed Zoning Ordinance, 1969 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Ellensburg One-way Street Proposal, 1968 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Ellensburg Planning Commission, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Ellensburg Planning Commission, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Ellensburg Planning Commission miscellaneous materials, 1960s (Box-folder 1-11)
- Ellensburg Planning Reports and Proposals, 1953-1968 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Ellensburg Zoning – Correspondence and reports, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Ellensburg Zoning – Newspaper clippings, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Ellensburg Zoning Ordinances, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Fruit Stand and County Sign Law, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Kittitas County Comprehensive Plan, 1961 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Kittitas County Comprehensive Plan, 1973 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Kittitas County Land Use Task Force, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Kittitas County Meeting on Recreation, Fish and Wildlife, 1973 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Kittitas County Regional Planning Council, 1969 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Kittitas County Shoreline Advisory Committee, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Kittitas County Shoreline Master Program, 1973 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Kittitas County Shoreline Master Program, 1974 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Kittitas County Shoreline Master Program Draft, 1974 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Kittitas County Subdivision Ordinance, 1970 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Kittitas County Tentative Zoning Resolution, 1959 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Kittitas County Tourism and Development Study, 1965 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Kittitas County Zoning Ordinance, 1968 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Miscellaneous notes, newspaper clippings (Box-folder 3-3)
- Review comments on draft report – Yakima Basin, 1973 (Box-folder 3-4)
- Shorelines Management, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Sulphur Creek Drainage Report, 1974 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Washington State Department of Ecology / Bureau of Reclamation Water Reports, 1977 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Washington State Water Program, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 3-8)
- United States Bureau of Reclamation Yakima Project Data, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Water Quality Management Plan, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3-10)
- Yakima Basin Industry and Water Discussion Paper, 1972 (Box-folder 3-11)
- Yakima Basin Study Ground Water, 1973 (Box-folder 3-12)
- Yakima Basin Study Goals and Objectives, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 3-13)
- Yakima Basin Study Population Report, 1973 (Box-folder 3-14)
- Yakima Level B Study Draft, 1975 (Box-folder 3-15)
- Yakima River Basin Citizen’s Committee, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Yakima River Basin Citizen’s Committee, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Yakima River Basin Citizen’s Committee – policies and procedures, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Yakima River Basin Fish and Wildlife Report, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Yakima River Basin Miscellaneous, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Yakima River Basin Newsletters, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Yakima River Basin Steering Committee, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project, 1982 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Yakima River Basin Water Quality Management Workshop, 1974 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Yakima River Basin Water Resource Management Program, 1977 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Yakima River Conservancy – Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 4-11)
- Yakima Valley Water Management Study, 1977 (Box-folder 4-12)
- Environmental Studies Committee, 1971 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Environmental Studies Program, 1972 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Environmental Studies Program, 1973 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Kittitas County Zoning Resolution, 1962 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Yakima River Conservancy Newsletter, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Kittitas County Weather, 1941-1988 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Kittitas Valley Historic data, Irrigation, Climate, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 6-2)
- History of Ellensburg Water System, 1959- (Box-folder 6-3)
- Ellensburg Formation, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Kittitas County Geomorphology, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 6-5)
- L.T. Murray Field Slides, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 6-6)
- Kittitas County Government Units, 1970- (Box-folder 6-7)
- Climate Change, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 6-8)
- Badger Pocket, 1973- (Box-folder 6-9)
- Kittitas County, 1973-1955 (Box-folder 6-10)
- Kittitas Valley, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 6-11)
- Geologic studies of Manastash, Umptanum, and Saddle Mountain, 1977- (Box-folder 6-12)
- Kittitas County Water Committee, 1977- (Box-folder 6-13)
- Ellensburg Climate, 1983-1970 (Box-folder 6-14)
- Swauk Winter recreation, 1986- (Box-folder 6-15)
- Swauk Corridor Winter Recreation, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 6-16)
- Smoke Event, 1989- (Box-folder 6-17)
- Notes- Patterned Ground in Central Washington, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Washington Almanac, 1962- (Box-folder 7-2)
- Notes- Geography Summer Field Camp, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Notes- Washington Environments, 1973- (Box-folder 7-4)
- Notes- Regional Geography, 1974- (Box-folder 7-5)
- Notes -Cascade Range, 1975- (Box-folder 7-6)
- Notes- Mt. Baker (Box-folder 7-7)
- Notes- Foster Creek, 1987- (Box-folder 7-8)
- Notes- Table Mountain, 1995- (Box-folder 7-9)
- Notes- Biotic Changes in Washington (Box-folder 7-10)
- Notes- Columbia basin and plateau (Box-folder 7-11)
- Notes- Palouse and Loess (Box-folder 7-12)
- Notes- Scrublands, -1977 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Notes- Washington Miscellaneous, -1977 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Notes-Weather Data, -1974 (Box-folder 8-12)
- Notes-Drought, 1930-1977 (Box-folder 8-1)
- Newspaper Clippings - Washington Weather, 1957-1998 (Box-folder 8-2)
- Newspaper Clippings –Weather, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 8-3)
- Timeline-Drought Chronology, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8-4)
- Notes-Drought in the Yakima Basin, 1977- (Box-folder 8-5)
- Notes-Drought in the Yakima River Basin, 1977- (Box-folder 8-6)
- Newspaper Clippings – Drought, 1977- (Box-folder 8-7)
- Newspaper Clippings – Weather, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 8-8)
- Newspaper Clippings - Snow Events, 1996- (Box-folder 8-9)
- Notes-Drought Related, 2001- (Box-folder 8-10)
- Newspaper Clippings - Global Warming, 2005- (Box-folder 8-11)
- Course work - Geology 22 Martin Kaatz, 1947- (Box-folder 9-1)
- Course work - Geography 260 Martin Kaatz (Box-folder 9-2)
- Notes- Mt. Rainier Glaciers, 1964-1984 (Box-folder 9-3)
- Notes- OSU remote sensing project, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 9-4)
- Article-Geography Department Hhistory, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 9-5)
- Article-What is Geography, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Memorial-Stoltman, 1981- (Box-folder 9-7)
- Article-History of Geography departments in Pacific Northwest, 1989- (Box-folder 9-8)
- Article-Geography at CWU, 1990- (Box-folder 9-9)
- Article-Geography Department History, 1990- (Box-folder 9-10)
- Correspondence- R.S. Funderburk, 1992- (Box-folder 9-11)
- Letter of Application and Vita from Karl Lillquist, 1995- (Box-folder 9-12)
- Manuscript-Uebecker Letter to Faculty Senate, 1996- (Box-folder 9-13)
- Article-Abstract Scientific Association 77th annual, 2004- (Box-folder 9-14)
- Memorial- Jakubek, Otto, 2006- (Box-folder 9-15)
- Notes-TIP Strategies Kittitas County, 2009- (Box-folder 9-16)
- Resume Martin Kaatz (Box-folder 9-17)
- Photographs Bean Slide, 2002- (Box-folder 10-1)
- Notes-Beverly Creek, 2002- (Box-folder 10-2)
- Photographs Beverly Creek Slide, 2002- (Box-folder 10-3)
- Notes-Geology Beverly Creek, 2002- (Box-folder 10-4)
- Photograph Notes Beverly and Bean, 2002- (Box-folder 10-5)
- Notes-Beverly Creek Debris Flow, 2002- (Box-folder 10-6)
- Notes-Flow 3, 2002- (Box-folder 10-7)
- Report-Beverly creek slide, 2004- (Box-folder 10-8)
- Notes -Beverly Creek, 2002- (Box-folder 10-9)
- Notes-Thorp Landslide, 1941-1962 (Box-folder 11-1)
- Notes-Mount Rainier Mud Flows, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 11-2)
- Notes-Yakima Canyon Debris Flow, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 11-3)
- Photographs-Thorp Slide, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11-4)
- Newspaper clippings-Thorp Slide, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11-5)
- Newspaper clippings-Mass Wasting, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11-6)
- Notes-County Mass Wasting History, 1971- (Box-folder 11-7)
- Notes-Second Thorp Slide, 1971- (Box-folder 11-8)
- Notes-Landslides Near Thorp, 1971- (Box-folder 11-9)
- Notes-Table Mountain Block Streams, 1972- (Box-folder 11-10)
- Bibliography –Landslides, 1977- (Box-folder 11-11)
- Notes -Stafford Creek, 2002- (Box-folder 11-12)
- Notes-Avalanche and Landslides (Box-folder 11-13)
- Notes-Debris flow (Box-folder 11-14)
- Notes-Mass wasting (Box-folder 11-15)
- Notes-Columbia Basin, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 12-1)
- Notes-Columbia Basin Project, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 12-2)
- Notes-Bibliographies, 1958-1994 (Box-folder 12-3)
- Notes-Columbia Basin Soils, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 12-4)
- Notes-Channeled Scabland, 1959-1984 (Box-folder 12-5)
- Notes-Vantage, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 12-6)
- Notes-Columbia Basin Basalt, 1979- (Box-folder 12-7)
- Notes-Columbia Basin Prehistory, 1982- (Box-folder 12-8)
- Notes-Gravel Deposits in the Pasco Basin, 1986- (Box-folder 12-9)
- Notes-Scabland and Waterville, 1998- (Box-folder 12-10)
- Bibliographies (Box-folder 12-11)
- Bibliographies- Patterned ground (Box-folder 12-12)
- Notes-Columbia Basin Development (Box-folder 12-13)
- Notes-Snoqualmie Pass (Box-folder 13-1)
- Article-The Roads of Luzon, 1948- (Box-folder 13-2)
- Publication-Lucas County Ohio Tourist Guide, 1952- (Box-folder 13-3)
- Notes-Kittitas County Agriculture, 1956- (Box-folder 13-4)
- Publication-Water the Number One Problem in Conservation, 1960- (Box-folder 13-5)
- Notes-World Population and Resources, 1960- (Box-folder 13-6)
- Notes-Camp Illahee (Teanaway Geology), 1961- (Box-folder 13-7)
- Notes-Geography 347 Field Trip, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 13-8)
- Reports -College Elementary School Camp, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 13-9)
- Article-Africa’s environmental problems, 1963- (Box-folder 13-10)
- Article-Automation Abundance and Leisure, 1964- (Box-folder 13-11)
- Notes-Earthquakes, 1965-1989 (Box-folder 13-12)
- Notes-Miscellaneous topics, 1965-2005 (Box-folder 13-13)
- Essays in Geomorpholgy, 1966- (Box-folder 13-14)
- Article-The Next 100 Years, 1967- (Box-folder 13-15)
- Miscellaneous Reports and Talks, 1967-2002 (Box-folder 13-16)
- Notes-Washington Geography (Box-folder 13-17)
- Notes-Rainier field trip, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 13-18)
- Notes-The Geography Behind the News, 1971- (Box-folder 13-19)
- Article-Impact of Non-resident College Students, 1971- (Box-folder 13-20)
- Notes, Miscellaneous Field, 1972-2009 (Box-folder 13-21)
- Notes-Ellensburg Climate Data, 1973- (Box-folder 13-22)
- Notes-Water Rights, 1977- (Box-folder 13-23)
- Notes-Status of Land, 1977- (Box-folder 13-24)
- Notes-Mineral Creek, 1982- (Box-folder 13-25)
- Notes-Ennis Quadrangle, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 13-26)
- Notes-Swauk, 1985- (Box-folder 13-27)
- Book Review-Tropical Nature, 1986- (Box-folder 13-28)
- Article-The Public and the Experts, 1989- (Box-folder 13-29)
- Notes-Wind Related, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 13-30)
- Notes-Kittitas County Land, 2001- (Box-folder 13-31)
- Notes-Ellensburg Development West Interchange, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 13-32)
- Notes-Floods Kittitas Valley, 1957-1996 (Box-folder 14-1)
- Notes-Clastic Dikes, 1967- (Box-folder 14-2)
- Notes-Earth’s Motion, 1967- (Box-folder 14-3)
- Notes-Geomorphology, 1969- (Box-folder 14-4)
- Notes-Mountain Climate and Environment, 1969- (Box-folder 14-5)
- Notes-Permafrost, 1969- (Box-folder 14-6)
- Notes-Futurism, 1970- (Box-folder 14-7)
- Notes-Washington Glaciation, 1974- (Box-folder 14-8)
- Notes-Fluvial Processes in Geomorphology, 1974- (Box-folder 14-9)
- Notes-Patterned ground, 1988- (Box-folder 14-10)
- Notes-Pediment, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 14-11)
- Notes-Land Use, 1975- (Box-folder 14-12)
- Notes-Climate Change, 1975- (Box-folder 14-13)
- Notes-Bio- Geomorphology, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 14-14)
- Notes-Pingos, 1977- (Box-folder 14-15)
- Notes-Mount Saint Helens, Notes of eruption impact locally, 1978- (Box-folder 14-16)
- Notes-Population, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 14-17)
- Notes-Unconfined Glaciers, 1981- (Box-folder 14-18)
- Article-Limits, 1986- (Box-folder 14-19)
- Notes-Winter Weather Ellensburg, 1996- (Box-folder 14-20)
- Notes-Rain on Snow, 1999- (Box-folder 14-21)
- Notes-Kittitas County Flood Task Force, 2011- (Box-folder 14-22)
- Notes-Geomorphic Relations between Frenchman Coulee and Babcock rock (Box-folder 14-23)
- Notes-Clear-Cutting, 1960-1991 (Box-folder 15-1)
- Notes-Forest Land, 1973-1991 (Box-folder 15-2)
- Notes-Forest Service Letters, 1987- (Box-folder 15-3)
- Notes-Silver Creek, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 15-4)
- Notes-Kittitas County Friends of the forest, 1986- (Box-folder 15-5)
- Notes-Wenatchee National Forest, 1986- (Box-folder 15-6)
- Notes-Salmon La Sac Road, 1987- (Box-folder 15-7)
- Notes-Rate of Harvest Timber, 1988- (Box-folder 15-8)
- Publication-Timber Fish And Wildlife work plan, 1988- (Box-folder 15-9)
- Notes-Timber Fish and Wildlife, 1989- (Box-folder 15-10)
- Notes-TFW Yakima, 1989- (Box-folder 15-11)
- Notes-Forestry Practices, 1989- (Box-folder 15-12)
- Notes-stream Corridor Management Symposium, 1998- (Box-folder 15-13)
- Notes-Yakima River Basin, 1958-1997 (Box-folder 16-1)
- Notes-Dams and Pacific Northwest Landscapes, 1965- (Box-folder 16-2)
- Notes-Mt Rainier Glaciation, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 16-3)
- Notes-Ellensburg Floods, 1969- (Box-folder 16-4)
- Notes-Yakima’s River Basin Water Resources, 1970-2001 (Box-folder 16-5)
- Notes-Economic Base of the Yakima Sub-region, 1973- (Box-folder 16-6)
- Notes-Geomorphic Central Washington, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 16-7)
- Notes-Kittitas Valley Floods, 1977-2010 (Box-folder 16-8)
- Notes-Yakima River Basin, 1977- (Box-folder 16-9)
- Notes-Floods Yakima Basin, 1977-2011 (Box-folder 16-10)
- Bibliography-Yakima Basin (Box-folder 16-11)
- Notes-Yakima River Basin Droughts, 1988- (Box-folder 16-12)
- Notes-Yakima RMP, 1991- (Box-folder 16-13)
- Notes-Flood Data Yakima River, 1996- (Box-folder 16-14)
- Notes-Ice Age Floods, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 16-15)
- Notes-Teanaway Basin, 2003- (Box-folder 16-16)
- Notes-Manastash Creek Water, 2008- (Box-folder 16-17)
- Publication-Teanaway River Site and Reach Assessment, 2010- (Box-folder 16-18)
- Photographs- Aerial- Bugni Property, 2010- (Box-folder 16-19)
- Notes- Yakima River Basin Notes, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 17-1)
- Publication-Yakima River Mile Index, 1968- (Box-folder 17-2)
- Notes- Yakima River Basin, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 17-3)
- Notes- Yakima basin Water, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 17-4)
- Notes- Yakima River Basin data, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 17-5)
- Notes- Yakima Citizens Committee Studies, 1973- (Box-folder 17-6)
- Notes- Miscellaneous Yakima River, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 17-7)
- Notes- Yakima Basin, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 17-8)
- Notes- Bumping Lake Expansion, 1975- (Box-folder 17-9)
- Bibliographies Yakima River (Box-folder 17-10)
- Notes-Yakima River and Nearby Glaciation, 1977- (Box-folder 17-11)
- Notes-Storage Studies Yakima River Basin, 1985- (Box-folder 17-12)
- Notes-Yakima Resource Management Plan, 1990- (Box-folder 17-13)
- Notes-Yakima River Basin Clearing House Discussions, 1990- (Box-folder 17-14)
- Notes-Yakima River Torrents, 1998- (Box-folder 17-15)
- Notes-Yakima canyon Storm Meteorology, 1999- (Box-folder 17-16)
- Notes-Hansen Pits, 2001- (Box-folder 17-17)
- Notes-Black Rock Reservoir Hammond, 2005- (Box-folder 17-18)
- Notes-Yakima Fold Belt (Box-folder 17-19)
- Thesis -Roads of Luzon-Martin Kaatz Master’s Thesis, 1948- (Box-folder 18-1)
- Thesis -The Black Swamp (Draft), 1952- (Box-folder 18-2)
- Thesis -The Black Swamp Published copies, 1953- (Box-folder 18-3)
- Thesis -The Black Swamp Bound Copy, 1952- (Box-folder 18-4)
- Thesis -The Black Swamp Original (Box-folder 18-5)
- Maps Thesis Maps (Box-folder 18-6)
- Maps Thesis Maps (Box-folder 18-7)
- Correspondence regarding Thesis (Box-folder 18-8)
- Correspondence with Department of Commerce, 1962- (Box-folder 19-1)
- Geomorphism, Central Washington, 1969- (Box-folder 19-2)
- Correspndence regarding cloud seeding, 1977- (Box-folder 19-3)
- Yakima River Basin Enhancement Project, 1982- (Box-folder 19-4)
- Columbia basin Notes, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 19-5)
- Geology of Yakima Country (Box-folder 19-6)
- Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project, 1982- (Box-folder 19-7)
- Yakima River Basin Enhancement Plan, 1989- (Box-folder 19-8)
- Bibliographies, Pacific Northwest, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 19-9)
- Bibliographic Note Cards (Box-folder 19-10)
- Bibliographic Note Cards (Box-folder 19-11)
- Notes for 35mm Slides (Box-folder 20-1)
- Photographs, Columbia Plateau, 1953- (Box-folder 20-2)
- Photographs, Umptanum Fold, 1961- (Box-folder 20-3)
- Aerial Photographs, Ellensburg, 1965- (Box-folder 20-4)
- Photographs, Patterned Ground, 1958- (Box-folder 20-5)
- Photographs, Kittitas Landforms, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 20-6)
- Photographs-Yakima canyon Mass Wasting, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 20-7)
- Photographs- Thorp Slide, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 20-8)
- Photographs- Thorp Slide, 1972- (Box-folder 20-9)
- Photographs-Ellensburg Formation, 1970- (Box-folder 20-10)
- Photographs- Ellensburg Floods, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 20-11)
- Photographs-Geology 386 Field Trip, 1974- (Box-folder 20-12)
- Photographs-Table Mountain, 1974- (Box-folder 20-13)
- Photographs- Swauk Corridor Winter Recreation, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 20-14)
- Photographs-Patterned Ground (Box-folder 20-15)
- Photographs, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 20-16)
- Photographs-Mass Wasting (Box-folder 20-17)
- Negatives (Box-folder 20-18)
- Negatives, Aerial Photos, 1969- (Box-folder 20-19)
- Negatives, Swauk Corridor, 1986- (Box-folder 20-20)
- Aerial Photographs, Lakes Kachess, Keechelus and Cle Elum, 1973- (Box-folder 20-21)
- Slides-Fans, Pediments, Terraces (Box-folder 21-1)
- Slides-Various Washington Landforms (Box-folder 21-2)
- Slides-Floods, Yakima River, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 21-3)
- Slides-Local Geography, Glaciers, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 21-4)
- Slides-Aerial Photographs Patterend Ground (Box-folder 21-5)
- Slides-Calgary British Columbia Field Trip, 1965- (Box-folder 21-6)
- Slides-Columbia Basin, 1986- (Box-folder 21-7)
- Slides-Weathering and Mass Wasting, 1989- (Box-folder 21-8)
- Slides-Limits Presentation, 1979- (Box-folder 21-9)
- Slides-Glaciers, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 21-10)
- Slides-Patterned Ground (Box-folder 21-11)
- Slides-Geologic, Western United States (Box-folder 21-12)
- Slides-Scablands Seminar, 1998- (Box-folder 21-13)
- Slides-Volcanism, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 21-14)
- Slides-Numbered 1-139 (Box-folder 22-1)
- Slides-Landslides, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 22-2)
- Slides-Various Geographic Features, 1959-1982 (Box-folder 22-3)
- Slides-Land Uses, 1956-1981 (Box-folder 22-4)
- Slides-Patterned Ground, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 22-5)
- Slides-Geographic features, 1959-1977 (Box-folder 22-6)
- Slides-Timber Industry, 1956-1975 (Box-folder 22-7)
- Slides-Land Use, 1979- (Box-folder 23-1)
- Slides-Farming, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 23-2)
- Slides-Various Photographs United States Geography, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 23-3)
- Slides-River Related, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 23-4)
- Slides-Mount Rainier Glaciation, 1956-1977 (Box-folder 23-5)
- Slides-Mount Rainier Glaciation, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 23-6)
- Slides-Mount Rainier Glaciation, 1956-1973 (Box-folder 23-7)
- Slides-Weathering and Mass Wasting, 1964-1984 (Box-folder 24-1)
- Slides-Weathering and Mass Wasting, 1960-1981 (Box-folder 24-2)
- Slides-Glaciation, 1954-1983 (Box-folder 24-3)
- Slides-Glaciation, 1955-1982 (Box-folder 24-4)
- Slides-Glaciation, 1959-1982 (Box-folder 24-5)
- Slides-Glaciation, 1961- (Box-folder 24-6)
- Slides-Kittitas Valley, 1957-1982 (Box-folder 25-1)
- Slides-Kittitas Valley, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 25-2)
- Slides-Manastash, Quartz, Cascade, 1956-1988 (Box-folder 25-3)
- Slides-Snoqualmie, 1961-1981 (Box-folder 25-4)
- Slides-Cascades, 1958-1983 (Box-folder 25-5)
- Slides-Mount Stuart, 1958-1987 (Box-folder 25-6)
- Slides-Mountain Landforms, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 25-7)
- Slides-Western United States, 1963-1979 (Box-folder 26-1)
- Slides-Dunes, 1960-1983 (Box-folder 26-2)
- Slides-Desert Landforms, 1959-1978 (Box-folder 26-3)
- Slides-Alluvial Fans, 1963-1980 (Box-folder 26-4)
- Slides-Faults, 1959-1980 (Box-folder 26-5)
- Slides-Geographic Landforms, 1959-1980 (Box-folder 26-6)
- Photo CDs, 2002-2011 (Box-folder 26-7)
- Photographs- Patterned Ground (Box-folder 27-1)
- Aerial Photographs, Lake Easton, Roslyn, 1973- (Box-folder 27-2)